In computer vision there are many algorithms that are designed to extract
在计算机视觉中 人们设计了很多算法来提取空间特征
spatial features and identify objects using information about image gradients.
并利用图像梯度信息来识别物体
One illustrative technique is called HOG or Histogram of Oriented Gradients.
其中一种技术叫做 HOG 也即方向梯度直方图
Histogram of Oriented Gradients may sound a little intimidating.
方向梯度直方图听着太高深了
So let's go through what these terms actually mean.
我们先来讲一下这些术语
A histogram is a graphical representation of the distribution of data.
直方图就是数据分布的一种图形表现
It looks a bit like a bar graph with bars of different heights.
看起来有点像柱形图 其柱形有不同的高度
Each bar represents a group of data that falls in a certain range of values,
每个柱形代表一组处于一定值范围的数据
also called bins, and taller bars indicate that more data falls into a certain bin.
这些柱形也称为组 柱形越高意味着某组数据越多
For example, say, you took a grayscale image.
以灰度图像为例
Say, this image of pancakes and wanted to display a histogram of intensity data.
假设你想绘制出这张薄饼图的强度数据直方图
We know that all these pixel values range from 0 to
我们知道像素值的范围在 0 到 255 之间
255 and we can create bins to partition these values into ranges.
所以我们可以把这些值分成若干组
I'll create 32 bins each holding a range of 8 pixel values 0 to 7,
我要创建 32 个组 每组包含 8 个像素值 所以第一组范围是 0 到 7、
8 to 15, and so on up to 248 to 255.
然后 8 到 15 以此类推一直到 248 到 255
Then to create a histogram we look at
要创建直方图
every pixel value in this image and put each one in its correct bin.
我们得来看看这张图里的各个像素值 将各像素值放到对应的组里
This image has a lot of bright values in the pancakes,
这张图的薄饼里有很多亮值
but a very dark background.
背景则很黑
So we get a histogram that looks like this.
所以直方图看起来是这样的
This histogram shows that there's
在这个直方图里 黑色像素明显堆积在一起
a distinct dark grouping of pixels- the background pixels,
这些是背景的像素
that fall in these low ranges.
这些像素都在这些低值范围里
And there's another bright grouping of pixels
明亮的像素也聚集在一起
that are often around a grayscale value of 200,
基本上都在灰度值 200 左右
which must be the majority of the pancake pixel values.
这肯定是薄饼的大部分像素值
So now we know what a histogram of grayscale values looks like.
看完灰度值的直方图
The next words we see are oriented gradients.
我们来讲下一个术语 方向梯度
Oriented just means the direction or orientation of an image gradient.
方向很简单 指的就是图像梯度的方向或朝向
And we've already discussed how both the magnitude and
我们已经讲了要怎么用 Sobel 算子来计算梯度的
the direction of a gradient can be calculated using an sobel operators.
幅值和方向了
So let's put this all together.
把三个术语结合在一起
HOG should produce a histogram of gradient directions in an image.
HOG 就是指一张有关图像梯度方向的直方图
As a first step, HOG takes in an image like
首先 HOG 会接受一张图像
this pancake image and calculates
如这张薄饼图 然后计算
the magnitude and direction of the gradient at each pixel.
每个像素的梯度幅值和方向
This can be a lot of information.
这其中蕴含的信息可不少
So it actually groups these pixels into
所以 HOG 实际上会把这些像素
larger square cells typically eight by eight or smaller grids for smaller pictures.
分成若干个较大的正方形单元 单元大小通常是 8 乘 8 如果图片小一些 单元也就小一些
For the eight by eight case,
如果是 8 乘 8 的单元
it will have 64 gradient values,
那就有 64 个梯度值
then for each of these cells it counts up how many of these gradients are in
HOG 会计算每个单元相同的梯度方向有多少
a certain direction and sums the magnitude of
将这些梯度的幅值相加
these gradients so that the strength of the gradients are accounted for.
得到梯度强度
Then HOG places all that directional data into a histogram.
接着 HOG 会把所有方向数据放到直方图里
Here I'm showing you nine bins or ranges of values,
这个直方图有九组 也就是九个值范围
but you can choose to use more bins to further divide your data.
不过你可以建立更多组来进一步分类数据
And this is the histogram of oriented gradients that the pancake edge turns into,
这就是薄饼边缘的方向梯度直方图
and HOG does this for every cell in the image.
HOG 会对图像的每个单元进行同样的处理
This histogram of oriented gradients is actually a feature vector.
这个方向梯度直方图实际上就是个特征向量
The next step will be to actually use these HOG features to train a classifier.
接下来 我们要用这些 HOG 特征来训练分类器
The idea is that among images of the same object at different scales and orientations,
思路就是对于物体相同但大小、方向不同的图像
the same pattern of HOG features can be used to
我们可以利用相同的 HOG 特征模式
detect the object wherever and however it appears.
来检测物体 而不管物体的位置和呈现方式
But first let's see how to implement HOG in code.
但我们先来看怎么用代码实现 HOG
This will be a multi-step process.
实现过程有好几步
So in this and the next few examples,
所以从这个例子开始 在接下来的几个例子中
I'll explain the algorithm in a video and then you can expect
我都会在视频里讲解相关算法
a code and text explanation to follow for further learning. 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
然后讲解代码并给出文本解释 以便你继续学习